when working with documents there may be
occasions where you need to protect the
document which will restrict access or
editing rights to the document as you
can see I have a demonstration document
on the screen in front of me and I'm
going to demonstrate how you can apply
to password to access to fail and also a
password to restrict any editing of the
document the next thing I need to do is
I need to navigate up to the top toolbar
and select the tools option and then
from the drop down the protect document
option this brings up the password
protect dialog box so in the very first
one which is set as password to open
this document I will just type in
password press ENTER and it will ask me
to enter that again and select ok if I
click here now that is set the password
but that won't be active till I've
actually see after document so if I just
go to file and I'll close the document
and they'll ask me if I want to see that
select yes so now the forms that when I
open that it will ask for a password
select your key and that will then open
the document another option is is to
restrict the editing of the document as
you can see at the moment I can probably
cursor in the document and make changes
I'll just don't do those changes so what
I need to do is I need to restrict the
editing so if I click on the tools' mint
button again and go down to protect
document and I'll just take off the
password I will then enter a password to
modify the document so anybody who
wishes to modify it must have the
password click it and ask the password
again select ok and again this won't be
active until I save the document so I'm
going to go to fail and Clause and then
make sure I select see if so now when I
click on it it will ask me for a
password
so if I want to modify that I must put
the password in I can't open the
document but I would have to click read
only if I didn't have the password and
then I would not be able to make any
changes no matter what I pressed they
could make a duplicate copy of the
document may changes but the original
copy would not be changed there's no way
anybody could change that without having
the actual password